嘿 怎么了？
Hey, what's going on?
我家门上有张纸条说 "过来摩妮卡家
I found a note on my door, "Come to Monica's.
带香槟和三剑客糖果棒"？
Bring champagne and a Three Musketeers bar"?
给我
Yeah, I'll take that.
发生什么事了？
What's up?
- 摩妮卡和我订婚了   - 我的天
- Monica and I are engaged.     - Oh, my God.
恭喜你 她人呢？
Congratulations. Where is she?
我订婚了 我订婚了
I'm engaged! I'm engaged!
她在那儿20分钟了 难道你没听到吗？
She's been there for 20 minutes. You didn't hear?
我以为有个小孩在叫 "我是同性恋 "
I thought it was a kid yelling, "I'm gay!"
- 可以带她进来了吗？ - 让她去吧 好成人
- Can I bring her in?     - Let her stay. It's sweet.
我要结婚了 我要做新娘了
I'm getting married! I'm gonna be a bride!
闭嘴
Shut up.
不 我不闭嘴 因为我订婚了
No, I will not shut up, because I'm engaged!
只敢说 你敢上来这儿当面告诉我？
Oh, big talk! Why don't you come here and say that to me?
我未婚夫会教训你
My fiancé will kick your ass.
来呀 20号 20号
Come on, apartment 20, apartment 20.
你去弄她进来 你锁住门 我躲在衣柜里
You get her in, you bolt the door, I'll be in the closet.
好 等一下
Okay, wait, wait, wait. Okay, shh.
好…
Okay. Um.
我只是要告诉你们我很爱你们…
I just want to say that I love you guys so, so much...
感谢大家都在这儿 在这个对我很特别的晚上
...and thank you for being here on my special night.
对我们特别的晚上
Our special night.
我的这一晚不会… 我们的这一晚…
It just wouldn't be my night... Our night...
如果不是因为你们和我… 要命
...if you weren't here to celebrate with me... Us. Damn it!
没关系 我愿意这是你的特别的一晚
It's okay, I want this to be your night too.
敬摩妮卡
To Monica.
等一下 停
Come on, wait, stop it.
- 好 敬摩妮卡   - 敬摩妮卡
- Okay, to Monica.     - To Monica.
你决定婚礼用的乐团了吗？ 我也能做音乐演出的
Have you decided on a band for the wedding, because I'm kind of musical.
她几小时前才订婚 我想她还没时间去想…
She got engaged a few hours ago, I doubt she's had time to think...
提到合奏 记得有人烧了我的房子吗？
Speaking of chiming in, remember burning my apartment?
是 你自求多福
Yeah, you're on your own.
我们换衣服出门 去广场饭店喝香槟
We should get dressed up and go have champagne at the Plaza.
- 喔 好啊   - 对
- Oh, okay!     - Yeah.
我不能待太晚
I can't stay too long.
我的要早起去试镜广告 精神必须要好
I gotta get up early for an audition. I gotta look good.
我要演一个19岁的人
I'm supposed to be playing a 19-year-old.
什么？
What?
你说要早起 是指1986年？
So when you said get up early, did you mean 1986?
你们不觉得我看上去像19岁？
You guys don't think I look 19?
19 我们以为你说90
Oh, 19! We thought you said 90.
噢
Oh.
- 好了 大伙儿 走吧   - 好
- Okay, everybody, let's go.     - Okay.
我剩下的糖还在吗？
Is my candy bar around here?
没了 你吃完了
No, you ate it all.
我就怕会这样
I was afraid of that.
你知道什么样的鞋子 能配这只戒指？
You know what shoes would look great with this ring?
钻石鞋子
Diamond shoes.
你还没换衣服？
You're not getting dressed.
知道我的意思吧？
Know what I mean?
知道 不过没时间了
Yeah, but I don't think we have time.
要举行婚礼了
There's gonna be a wedding.
你要做新娘了
You're gonna be the bride.
有200人会看到你穿着白纱
Two hundred people are gonna be looking at you in a clean, white dress.
来吧
Let's do it.
钱德 很多人都会这样
Chandler, it happens to lots of guys.
你累了 喝了太多香槟
You're tired, you had a lot of champagne.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
我不担心 我很惊讶
I'm not worried. I'm fascinated.
知道吗？就像生物学一样
You know? It's like biology.
很好笑 高中时我的生物被当…
Which is funny, because in high school I failed biology...
今晚生物学当掉我
...and tonight biology failed me.
听看看 来宾进场时我要唱这首 好…
Check it out. I could play this while the guests are coming in, okay.
第一次见到钱德时 我以为他是同性恋
First time I met Chandler I thought he was gay
但我现在在他的婚礼上唱歌
But here I am singing On his wedding day
菲比 不要
Phoebe, no.
如果让我唱完 后面说他大概不是同性恋
If you'd let me finish, it goes on to say that he's probably not gay.
你们没有这个问题 你们是木头做的
You guys don't have this problem, you're made of wood.
- 嘿   - 嘿 你看来很不错
- Hey, you look great.     - Hey.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
你还好吗？
You okay over there?
我也不知道？觉得有一点…
I don't know. You know? I feel a little...
你知道吗？没关系 我会没事的
You know what? Never mind. I'll be fine.
别担心 你大概只是累了 喝了太多香槟
Don't worry about it. You're probably tired, you had a lot of champagne.
每个人都会的
It happens to everybody.
- 嘿 哇   - 嗨
- Hey. Wow.     - Hi.
- 摩妮卡之夜快乐   - 谢谢 你也一样
- Happy Monica's Night.     - Well, thank you. You too.
你能相信吗？他们真的要结婚了？
Can you believe they are actually getting married?
是啊 我常常结婚
Well, sure, but I get married all the time.
- 你还好吗？ - 我想是吧
- You okay?     - Yeah, I guess.
你觉得我们会不会有那么一天？
Do you think we'll ever have that?
你说"我们" 是指你和我？
You mean "we," you and me?
不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no.
"我们"是指你和别人 我和别人
"We," you with someone, me with someone.
还好 吓了我一跳
Good, you scared me a minute.
是啊 好可怕
I know. Shake it off.
因为我们俩在一起是噩梦
It's just because you and I, we were like a nightmare.
- 可是也有好时光   - 当然 就像那次…
- No, but there were some good times.     - Absolutely. Like there was...
- 你总想得起一点好的吧   - 给我一分钟
- Surely you can think of something.     - Just give me a minute.
对了
Oh, well, yes.
- 我想得出一件好事   - 是什么？
- I can think of one good thing.     - What?
你总是很…
You were always good at the...
在行
...at the, uh, the stuff.
是啊…
Yeah, I...
我很在行？
I was good at the stuff?
对
Mm-hm. Yup.
我真的很喜欢你的手
I really liked your hands.
- 我的手？ - 对
- My hands?     - Yeah.
- 是吗？ - 额
- Yeah?     - Uh-huh.
做得好 兄弟
Way to go, guys.
你也有很多事很在行
You were really good at the stuff too.
我知道
Oh, I know.
嘿 你知道我们从没做过什么吗？
Hey, you know what we never did?
不是那个啦
Oh, no, not that.
我们从没有过"红利"夜
We never had bonus night.
- 什么？ - "红利"夜
- A what?     - You know, bonus night.
两个人分手了 然后见面度过最后一夜
Two people break up, but they get back together for one night.
最后一夜 只是上床？ 没有其他？
One night, just sex? No strings attached?
对 我们从来没有过
Yeah, yeah, we never had that.
- 没有   - 没有
- No.     - No.
好 这有一点怪怪的
Okay, this is getting a little crazy.
额 我是说…
Um, I mean...
我相信一定会很棒的…
...I'm sure it would be amazing...
但我想这不是个好主意
...but I really don't think it would be a good idea.
我真的…
I really...
真的…
...really...
不
...don't.
怎么样？
What's up?
怎么样 老兄？
What's up, dude?
要什么随便拿 不要伤害我
Take whatever you want, just don't hurt me.
你玩电动游戏吧 嗯？
You playing a little PlayStation, huh?
有够逊
That's wack.
电动游戏很逊
PlayStation is wack.
怎么样 逊电动游戏 怎么样？
What's up with the wack PlayStation, what's up?
哈？
Huh?
怎么 像不像19岁？
Come on, am I 19 or what?
对 从一到十评分 十分是一个人看来最笨的样子…
Yes, on a scale of one to 10, 10 being the dumbest a person can look...
你绝对是19
...you are definitely 19.
真的 多大？
Come on, really. How old?
很年轻 你是男人孩子 好吗？
Young. You're a man-child, okay?
去换衣服 大家都准备好了 拜托 拜托 内裤别还我
Now get changed, everybody's ready. And please, please, keep my underwear.
- 谢谢   - 不客气
- Oh, thanks.     - Okay.
- 乔…   - 干嘛？
- Joe.     - Yeah.
额
Uh.
你和人上床很多次 对不对？
You've had a lot of sex, right?
何时 今天？
When, today?
有几次 没有很多
Some, not a lot.
我问你是因为我有一点…
The reason I'm asking is because I had kind of a, uh...
我不能…
I was unable to...
我很想 可是不能…
I really wanted to, but I couldn't...
是这样…
There, ha, hm.
我发生了一个意外
There was an incident.
不要担心 有时会这样的
Don't worry about that, man. That happens.
- 你也这样过？ - 对 有一次
- It's happened to you?     - Yeah, once.
- 那你怎么办？ - 照样做啊
- Well, what'd you do?     - I did it anyway.
菲比 快点 我们走吧
Phoebe, come on, let's go.
快点
Come on.
你为什么还没换衣服？
Why aren't you dressed yet?
抱歉 我替你的婚礼写出了最佳歌曲
I'm sorry. But I wrote the best song for your wedding.
- 听听看 - 不 菲比
- Check this out.     - No Phoeb.
如果你现在换好衣服 你就可以在婚礼演出
If you get ready now, you can play.
- 真的？ - 对
- Really?    - Yes.
太令人兴奋了 谢谢你
That's so exciting! Thanks, Mon.
可是如果你再动我的吉他 我就会打你
But if you touch my guitar again, I'll have to pound on you a little bit.
好吧 去准备出门 我去叫大家
Fair enough. Get ready. I'll get everybody.
终于可以开始庆祝我的…
Finally we can start celebrating my...
对不起 显然 我打开了通往过去的门
I'm sorry, apparently I opened the door to the past.
好 摩妮卡 你刚刚看到的是…
Okay, Monica, Mon. Okay, what you just saw...
可以问你一个小小问题吗？ 为什么要在今晚？
Can I ask you just a little question? Why tonight?
- 什么？ - 我花了一辈子等着订婚…
- What?     - I waited my whole life to be engaged.
不像某些人 我只计划做一次
And unlike some, I only plan on doing this once.
可能这很自私 我很抱歉 但我希望这是今晚的焦点
Maybe it's selfish, I'm sorry, but I hoped tonight could just be about that.
- 甜心 这是今晚的焦点啊   - 这是今晚的焦点啊
- Oh, honey, but it is.     - No, it's not.
不 现在焦点是你们的复合
Now it's about you getting back together.
你看 你们抢了我的锋头
See, you kind of stole my thunder.
好 等等 我们没有抢了你的锋头 因为我们没有要复合
We did not steal your thunder. We are not getting back together.
- 是啊 反正也没有人看到   - 没错
- Yeah, no, and nobody even saw.     - Yeah.
是真的
That's true.
- 我们只是吻了一下   - 只是一个吻
- We just kissed.     - It was just a kiss.
你们吻了？
You guys kissed?
那是什么意思？
What does this mean?
你们复合了吗？ 我可以在你们婚礼上演唱吗？
Are you back together? Can I sing at your wedding?
锋头被抢了
Thunder being stolen.
- 菲比 没有什么   - 不要小事化大
- Phoebe, it's nothing.     - Let's not make a big deal of this.
只发生一次 根本不算什么
It was a one-time thing. It doesn't even matter.
我的天
Oh, my God.
你们竟然在谈论这件事
I cannot believe you guys are talking about this.
卧房里的问题是他们两人之间的事
Problems in the bedroom are between a man and woman.
好吗？钱德已经尽力了
All right? Now, Chandler is doing the best he can.
我想他们不是在讨论这事 乔
I don't think that's what they were talking about.
真是好 钱德不行 他们亲吻了
What a great night. Chandler can't do it, they kissed.
- 什么？ - 你们亲了？大条了
- What?     - You guys kissed? This is huge.
不 这不大条
No, it's not huge.
大家觉得这事大条 让摩妮卡觉得…
People thinking it's huge has led Monica to believe...
我们抢了她的锋头 我们没有
...we're stealing her thunder, which we aren't.
我们还在谈这件事 不是吗？
We're still talking about it.
那件事 还有钱德的问题
That, and Chandler's problem.
摩妮卡…听着…
Monica, listen, listen.
如果我们不再谈罗斯和瑞秋 你会不会觉得好一点？
Would you feel better if we stopped talking about Ross and Rachel?
- 会很好   - 没问题
- That would be lovely.     - You got it.
来 我看起来可以像19岁吧？
Now, I can pass for 19, right?
对 你可以看起来像19岁
Yes, you can pass for 19.
- 真的？ - 对
- Really?     - Yes.
- 认真的？ - 认真的？
- Seriously?     - Seriously?
认真的说 不 你可以扮演 你的年纪 也就是31岁
Seriously, no. Okay? You can play your own age, which is 31.
我30岁
I'm 30!
乔伊 你不是 你31岁
Joey, you are not. You're 31.
真烂
Oh, crap!
好 去广场饭店 叫些迈泰？ 不过你可能不能再喝了
So, the Plaza. We'll get some mai tais? Maybe no more for you though.
我不想去了
You know, I think I don't feel like going to the Plaza.
- 为什么？ - 摩妮卡 这太可笑了
- Why?     - This is ridiculous.
我不想谈这件事 尤其是和你
I don't want to talk about it. I don't. Especially with you.
有够逊
Pssh. That is wack.
是吗？
Yeah?
好 我会在婚礼唱这首歌
I'll play it at the wedding.
好 不过要看他们 是不是真的让你演唱
Yeah, well, we'll see if they actually let you play, huh?
他们会说你想听的话…
They tell you anything you want to hear...
像是 "你看起来像19岁"
...like, "You look 19."
然后又反悔 说 "不 你不像"
Then they just take it away, like, "No, you don't."
这件事摩妮卡不会反悔的
Monica won't take this away.
- 她不会吗？ - 她会吗？
- Wouldn't she?     - Would she?
她会吗？
Would she?
你吃了我的糖果
You ate my candy bar!
猜猜是谁
Guess who.
嘿
Hey.
我刚发现 我们似乎还有些事没解决
Hey, I just realized we kind of left some stuff up in the air.
你认为摩妮卡说
What did Monica mean
"我不想谈"特别是和我 是什么意思？
"I don't want to talk," especially with me?
为什么不特别是你和我？ 是我们两人在接吻耶
Why not especially you and me? We were both kissing.
你还在想那件事？
Still thinking about it?
我是认真的 她说 "尤其是你" 是什么意思？
I'm serious. What did she mean by that? "Especially you."
- 谁在乎啊？ - 我在乎
- Oh, who cares?     - I care.
我也在乎
And so do I.
我要和她谈谈 让我换衣服好吗？
I have to talk to her. Will you let me get changed?
好啊 没问题
Okay, sure.
我要让你看我换衣服吗？
Am I going to let you watch me?
不
No.
我不相信她竟然如此 她就是这样
I can't believe her. It's just so typical.
摩妮卡 我知道你不高兴 可别忘了要举行婚礼了
I know you're upset, but don't forget there is going to be a wedding.
你会要丢捧花 然后去蜜月
You are going to throw the bouquet, and then a honeymoon.
- 可能去巴黎   - 巴黎？
- Maybe in Paris.     - Paris?
我们会在月光下的 那叫什么来着的大道上散步
We will take a moonlit walk on the Rue de la blah-blah-blah.
继续说
Keep talking.
会在床上洒玫瑰块花辫 做爱…
We will sprinkle rose petals on the bed and make love...
不是因为那很浪漫 而是因为我可以
...not just because it's romantic, but because I can.
我爱你
I love you.
嗯
Mmm.
先生
Bonjour, monsieur.
别说话 你会吓跑它
Don't say anything, you might scare it away.
这是巴黎 谁知道我们在这里？
It's Paris. Who knows we're here?
菲比 什么事？
Hi, Pheebs. What's up?
你说我可以在你的婚礼演唱 所以我要订金
You said I could sing at your wedding, so I need a small deposit.
- 什么？ - 你知道 一笔钱来保留那个日期
- What?     - Good-faith money to hold the date.
我们不会给你订金
We're not giving you a deposit for our wedding.
喔 我懂了
Oh, I see.
他们真能伤你的心 不是吗？
They break your heart, don't they?
我不需要他们的同意
You know, I don't really need their permission.
你想在他们婚礼唱歌 就在他们婚礼唱歌
You want to sing at their wedding, sing at their wedding.
如果你想看起来像19岁 就…
Yeah, and if you want to look 19, then you...
你要修饰一下你的眼睛
You got to do something about your eyes.
怎么？我的眼睛怎么了？
What's wrong with my eyes?
他们出卖了你 里头有太多的智慧
They give you away. There's too much wisdom in there.
在上面放茶袋敷15分钟
Put some tea bags on them for 15 minutes.
- 也会去除我的智慧？ - 也许你只需要10分钟
- That'll get rid of my wisdom?     - Maybe 10 minutes for you.
给她订金 给她戒指 我不在乎
Give her the deposit, give her the ring. I don't care.
- 什么事？ - 摩妮卡 你是什么意思 当你说…
- Yes?     - What did you mean when you said...
你不想和任何人谈 尤其是我？
...you didn't want to talk to anyone, especially me?
好棒的道歉 你接受了 再见
What a great apology. And you accept it. Bye-bye.
不 我是认真的 "特别是和我"是怎么回事？
No, seriously, what was the "especially me" part about?
这样说吧 这不是你第一次抢了我的锋头
Let's just say it's not the first time you've stolen my thunder.
哇？
Wha?
我觉得…
Hey, here's a thought...
摩妮卡 你在说什么？
Monica, what are you talking about?
我16岁的生日宴会上 记得你和我表哥查理上三垒
My sweet 16. You went to third base with my cousin Charlie.
啊 上三垒
Ah, third base.
每个人都在讲那件事
It was all everybody could talk about.
摩妮卡 那会发生是因为你的宴会太无聊
The only reason I did that was because your party was so boring.
- 我们请了一捆漫画家   - 哦
- We had a caricaturist.     - Oh.
当我结婚时 猜猜不会请谁来演唱
Whenever I get married Guess who won't be asked to sing
叫盖勒的还有叫宾的
Somebody named Geller And somebody else named Bing
摩妮卡 你的甜蜜16岁生日 是一百万年前的事了
Monica, your sweet 16 was like a million years ago.
而你现在又再做了一次
Yet here you are doing it again.
我不想抢你的笨锋头
Oh, I don't want to steal your stupid thunder.
那还有什么原因你会和罗斯亲热？
Why else would you have made out with Ross?
我不知道
Got me.
够了啦 时机已过 不会发生了
Easy, mimey, the moment has passed. It ain't gonna happen.
如果今晚的注意力都在我身上就好了
It'd be nice if I could have this night.
我发誓 我从没有想要过抢你的锋头
I never wanted any part of your night.
不应该有人看到我们接吻的
No one was supposed to see us.
所以你们就在秘密走廊上做 因为没有人会到那儿去？
Is that why you did it in the secret hallway, where nobody ever goes?
瑞秋 我想过了
Uh, Rachel, I've been thinking.
我觉得我们今晚 在一起的主意不是很好
I don't think us getting together tonight is such a good idea.
我退出
I'm calling it off.
挽救尊严的好方法
Way to save your dignity, my man.
摩妮卡 我为什么要抢走 属于你的晚上？
Mon, why, why would I ever want to take away from your night?
我不知道 也许你有一点生气
I don't know, maybe you feel a little resentful.
也许你以为你会先结婚
Maybe you thought you'd get married first.
也许你不能忍耐…
Maybe you can't stand...
你那个以前很胖的朋友会先结婚
...that your formerly fat friend is getting married first.
哦…你知道吗？太不公平了
Oh, wow, that... You know what? That is so unfair.
知道吗？现在我想抢你锋头了
Now I want to steal your thunder.
罗斯 走 我们做爱去
Come on, Ross. Let's go have sex!
不敢相信 你竟然在我的订婚夜做爱
I can't believe you're gonna have sex on my engagement night.
总得有人做啊
Well, somebody should.
如果我们要做…
Look, if we're gonna do this...
我们没有要做 只是要让她以为我们有
We're not. She's just gonna think we are.
我懂了 人人都是赢家
I see, so everybody wins.
- 是谁？ - 是摩妮卡 开门
- Who is it?     - It's Monica, open up.
罗斯 停一下 拜托 等一下
Okay, Ross, stop it. Please, wait a minute.
哦
Ow!
宝贝 你喜欢吗？
Yeah, you like that, baby?
有什么事吗？
May we help you?
我要告诉你 我希望你们上床 希望你们复合
I wanted to say I hope you have sex, and I hope you get back together.
我警告你 你宣布订婚那一晚…
I warn you, the night you announce your engagement...
我会宣布我怀孕了
...I'm going to announce that I'm pregnant.
那怎么可能呢？
How is that ever going to happen?
摩妮卡 你想知道今晚 我为什么会和罗斯在一起？
Do you want to know why I was with Ross tonight?
- 我知道为什么   - 你不知道
- I know why.     - You don't.
- 好 为什么？ - 因为我很伤心
- Okay, why?     - Because I was sad.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
听着 我很…
Look, I am so...
很为你们高兴
...so happy for you guys.
但你要结婚这件事 提醒了我 我没有
But you getting married reminds me of the fact that I'm not.
八字都没一撇
I'm not even close.
也许我只想让自己好过一点
Maybe I just wanted to make myself feel better.
我知道这很笨 可是罗斯结婚时…
I know that that's dumb, but you were so depressed...
你沮丧得和钱德上床
...when Ross got married, you slept with Chandler.
我无所谓 和她上床的是我
I don't care, she slept with me.
甜心 很抱歉毁了属于你的今晚
Anyway, sweetie, I am so sorry I ruined your night.
我很抱歉我几乎让你和罗斯上床
I'm sorry I almost made you sleep with Ross.
我要走了
I'm gonna take off.
- 恭喜   - 谢谢
- Congratulations, man.     - Thanks.
- 瑞秋…   - 什么？
- And Rachel.     - Yeah.
我能说什么呢？
What can I say?
你失去了你的机会
You missed your chance.
从现在起 只有我能享受他们了
From now on, the only person who's going to enjoy these bad boys is me.
我们以为菲比会离开
We thought Phoebe would leave
但她留了下来
But she just stayed and stayed
没错 我整夜留在这里
That's right, I'm here all night
钱德永远不会…
And Chandler will never get...
来 这儿是一块钱
Hey, here's a dollar.
算是订金 请在我婚礼上演唱
Consider it a deposit. Please sing at our wedding.
- 哦 谢谢   - 好
- Oh, thank you      - Okay.
现在谁会在婚礼表演
Now who will perform the ceremony?
谁会在婚…
Who will perform the cer...?
啊
Oh, oh.
我早上再来打他
I'll pound on him in the morning.